<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<gallery accordion="true">

	<directions>
		<![CDATA[<p>Go through this slideshow to see the different branches of the government and information about them.</p><p>Select "Continue" to begin.</p>]]>
	</directions>

	<photo src="flash/jQuery/images/lo5_s5_img1_legislativeBranch.jpg" title="Legislative Branch">
  
		<info><![CDATA[<h4>Article I (One) "Congress"</h4><li>Makes the laws ("legislates")</li><li>Made up of the House of Representatives and the Senate</li><li>Voters choose representatives and senators</li><li>House of Representatives has two-year terms</li><li>A representative must be at least 25 years of age , a citizen for at least seven years, and living in the state that they represent</li><li>Senate has six-year terms</li><li>A senator must be at least 30 years of age, a citizen for at least nine years, and living in the state that they represent</li><li>Representatives and senators may be re-elected</li><li>435 representatives divided among the states by population, and 3 representatives for the federal capital, Washington D. C.</li><li>100 sentators, two from each state</li><li>Meets in the U.S. Capitol  Building</li>]]></info>
		<copyright><![CDATA[Public Domain]]></copyright>
	</photo>
	
	<photo src="flash/jQuery/images/lo5_s5_img2_executiveBranch.jpg" title="Executive Branch">
   
		<info><![CDATA[<h4>Article II (Two) "President"</h4><li>Carries out the laws</li><li>Made up of the President, Vice President, the Cabinet, and other heads of federal agencies and their staff</li><li>The president and vice president are elected to four-year terms</li><li>The president (and vice president) must be at least 35 years of age, a natural-born citizen, and living in the United States for at least 14 years</li><li>The Electoral College is the voting system for choosing the president</li><li>The president may not serve more than two terms (22nd Amendment)</li><li>The president appoints Cabinet members and the Senate confirms them</li><li>The vice president can break tied votes in the Senate</li><li>Meets in the White House</li>]]></info>
		<copyright><![CDATA[© 2011 AP Images]]></copyright>
	</photo>
	
	<photo src="flash/jQuery/images/lo5_s5_img3_judicialBranch.jpg" title="Judicial Branch- ">

		<info><![CDATA[<h4>Article III (Three) "Supreme Court"</h4><li>Interprets the laws and Constitution</li><li>The Supreme Court, is the only court created by the Constitution</li><li>Nine Supreme Court justices (one Chief Justice and eight associate justices)</li><li>Supreme Court justices serve for life--until death, retirement, or removal by Congress</li><li>The president appoints a justice when there is an opening and the Senate confirms the person chosen</li><li>Meets in the U.S. Supreme Court Building</li>]]></info>
		<copyright><![CDATA[© 2011 AP Images]]></copyright>
	</photo>
	
	
	
	

</gallery>