<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<gallery accordion="true">

	<directions>
		<![CDATA[<p>View this slideshow to see how later amendments have increased voter participation.</p><p>Select "Continue" to begin.</p>]]>
	</directions>

	<photo src="flash/jQuery/images/02_08_08_01.jpg" title=" ">
    <audio src="flash/jQuery/audio/02_08_08_01.mp3" />
		<info><![CDATA[<p>Alfred R. Waud created this image in 1867. Titled &quot;The First Vote,&quot; we can see African Americans lined up ready to cast their votes for the first time. Drawings such as this one show that African Americans valued this right of citizenship.</p>]]></info>
		<copyright><![CDATA[Public Domain]]></copyright>
	</photo>
	
	<photo src="flash/jQuery/images/02_08_08_02.jpg" title=" ">
    <audio src="flash/jQuery/audio/02_08_08_02.mp3" />
		<info><![CDATA[<p>This image shows the state legislature of South Carolina after the Civil War. You can see that most of the representatives were African American. Without the 13th, 14th, and 15th amendments, this would not have been possible.</p>]]></info>
		<copyright><![CDATA[Public Domain]]></copyright>
	</photo>
	
	<photo src="flash/jQuery/images/02_08_08_03.jpg" title=" ">
    <audio src="flash/jQuery/audio/02_08_08_03.mp3" />
		<info><![CDATA[<p>&quot;I remember my dad telling me, 'I can't believe the first time women vote is also the first time you will vote.' He was so excited, and so was I. He took me to the polls and told everyone about it.&quot;<br /><br />In 1920, Catherine Lewis was old enough to vote and, because of the 19th Amendment, able to vote as a woman. In this quote, she recalls casting her first vote in the election for president that year. Not only was she eager to vote, but her father was happy about the fact as well.</p>]]></info>
		<copyright><![CDATA[Public Domain]]></copyright>
	</photo>
	
	<photo src="flash/jQuery/images/02_08_08_04.jpg" title=" ">
    <audio src="flash/jQuery/audio/02_08_08_04.mp3" />
		<info><![CDATA[<p>&quot;I voted the first time we got the vote. It just felt like I was getting a little more privilege. It was something new for us.&quot;<br /><br />Ila Black Cuthbertson was 27 in 1920. She voted for the first time in the presidential election that year. Here she expresses how she felt about finally being able to cast a vote.</p>]]></info>
		<copyright><![CDATA[Public Domain]]></copyright>
	</photo>
	
	<photo src="flash/jQuery/images/02_08_08_05.jpg" title=" ">
    <audio src="flash/jQuery/audio/02_08_08_05.mp3" />
		<info><![CDATA[<p>&quot;Many of the men said if their wives voted, they would leave them. Even my mother didn't want to vote the first time. My husband, he said to vote the way I wanted, and he would vote the way he wanted.&quot;<br /><br />Blanche Benton also was one of the first women to vote in 1920. She expresses how exercising the right to vote was a difficult decision for some women. Though women now had the right, not everyone supported women voting. Benton shows how this was a personal struggle for some women.</p>]]></info>
		<copyright><![CDATA[Public Domain]]></copyright>
	</photo>
	
	<photo src="flash/jQuery/images/02_08_08_06.jpg" title=" ">
    <audio src="flash/jQuery/audio/02_08_08_06.mp3" />
		<info><![CDATA[<p>&quot;Do you know I've never voted in my life, never been able to exercise my right as a citizen because of the poll tax?&quot;<br />&quot;Mr. Trout&quot; to Mr. Pike, interviewer, Atlanta, Georgia. American Life Histories, 1936 - 1940.<br /><br />
A &quot;Mr. Trout&quot; made this remark in an interview in the late 1930s. In 1964, the states ratified the 24th Amendment. The states could no longer charge people to vote, called a &quot;poll tax.&quot; If &quot;Mr. Trout&quot; was still alive in 1964, he may have finally been able to exercise his right to vote.</p>]]></info>
		<copyright><![CDATA[© 2011 Thinkstock]]></copyright>
	</photo>
	
	<photo src="flash/jQuery/images/02_08_08_07.jpg" title=" ">
    <audio src="flash/jQuery/audio/02_08_08_07.mp3" />
		<info><![CDATA[<p>&quot;There can be no one too poor to vote.&quot;<br /><br />President Lyndon B. Johnson made this remark at a ceremony for the 24th Amendment. He declares that now money is no longer an issue when it comes to exercising the right to vote.</p>]]></info>
		<copyright><![CDATA[© 2011 Thinkstock]]></copyright>
	</photo>
	
	<photo src="flash/jQuery/images/02_08_08_08.jpg" title=" ">
    <audio src="flash/jQuery/audio/02_08_08_08.mp3" />
		<info><![CDATA[<p>&quot;It is men and women my age who are fighting the war in Iraq and dying in it. Students who vote can claim a voice in a system that ignores youth concerns.&quot;<br /><br />Prior to 1972, most states required voters to be at least 21 years of age. In this year, the 26th Amendment passed, lowering the voting age to 18. Americans thought that people who were old enough to marry, fight in a war, and own a business ought to be able to vote as well. Amelia Hershberger made this similar comment in a letter in 2004, referencing U.S. soldiers in Iraq.</p>]]></info>
		<copyright><![CDATA[© 2011 Thinkstock]]></copyright>
	</photo>
	
	<photo src="flash/jQuery/images/02_08_08_09.jpg" title=" ">
    <audio src="flash/jQuery/audio/02_08_08_09.mp3" />
		<info><![CDATA[<p>Since the 26th Amendment passed, many Americans have worked to encourage young voters to exercise their right to vote. This young woman was 18 at the time of this photo. She is shown here examining a polling machine. An organization sponsored transportation and education for young voters in her city of Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania. Their efforts helped her to vote on Election Day.</p>]]></info>
		<copyright><![CDATA[***** VERIFY IMAGE PERMISSION!!! *****]]></copyright>
	</photo>
	
	<photo src="flash/jQuery/images/02_08_08_10.jpg" title=" ">
    <audio src="flash/jQuery/audio/02_08_08_10.mp3" />
		<info><![CDATA[<p>This table shows national voting data for the 2008 presidential election. Without the 15th, 19th, 24th, and 26th amendments, how might this information be different?<br /><br />The percents for women, African Americans, and 18–24-year-olds would be much lower, as only a few states allowed those groups to vote before these amendments. The data tell us that these amendments have expanded the right to vote in the United States.<br /><br />With each extension of voting rights, more people can participate in government. Government can better respond to the people's wishes.
</p>]]></info>
		<copyright><![CDATA[Public Domain]]></copyright>
	</photo>

</gallery>