<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<gallery accordion="true">

	<directions>
		<![CDATA[<p>View this slideshow to see how later amendments have increased voter participation.</p><p>Select "Continue" to begin.</p>]]>
	</directions>

	<photo src="flash/jQuery/images/02_09_06_01.jpg" title=" ">
 
		<info><![CDATA[<p>Would give Congress the power to limit, control, or possibly prohibit work for those under 18 years of age.<br /><br /><br />*approved (proposed) by Congress in 1924 but not ratified by the states</p>]]></info>
		<copyright><![CDATA[© 2011 AP Images]]></copyright>
	</photo>
	
	<photo src="flash/jQuery/images/02_09_06_02.jpg" title=" ">

		<info><![CDATA[<p>Would limit how many times a person could be elected to serve in the House of Representatives or Senate.</p>]]></info>
		<copyright><![CDATA[Medioimages/Photodisc]]></copyright>
	</photo>
	
	<photo src="flash/jQuery/images/02_09_06_03.jpg" title=" ">

		<info><![CDATA[<p>Would require equal amounts of income and spending of the federal government each year.</p>]]></info>
		<copyright><![CDATA[© 2011 Thinkstock]]></copyright>
	</photo>
	
	<photo src="flash/jQuery/images/02_09_06_04.jpg" title=" ">

		<info><![CDATA[<p>Would end the Electoral College method of electing the president in favor of a direct national election.</p>]]></info>
		<copyright><![CDATA[Digital Vision]]></copyright>
	</photo>
	
	<photo src="flash/jQuery/images/02_09_06_05.jpg" title=" ">

		<info><![CDATA[<p>Would prohibit the use of the death penalty as punishment anywhere in U.S. territory.</p>]]></info>
		<copyright><![CDATA[&copy; 2011 AP Images]]></copyright>
	</photo>
	
	<photo src="flash/jQuery/images/02_09_06_06.jpg" title=" ">

		<info><![CDATA[<p>Would make certain images and actions related to the U.S. flag (such as burning the flag in protest) against the Constitution.</p>]]></info>
		<copyright><![CDATA[&copy; 2010 AP Images]]></copyright>
	</photo>
	
	<photo src="flash/jQuery/images/02_09_06_07.jpg" title=" ">

		<info><![CDATA[<p>Would allow naturalized citizens at least 20 years old to run for president.</p>]]></info>
		<copyright><![CDATA[© 2011 Thinkstock]]></copyright>
	</photo>
	
	<photo src="flash/jQuery/images/02_09_06_08.jpg" title=" ">

		<info><![CDATA[<p>Would establish English as the official language of the United States, requiring public signs and notices to be printed in English and no other language, and English-only instruction in public schools.</p>]]></info>
		<copyright><![CDATA[Public Domain]]></copyright>
	</photo>
	
	<photo src="flash/jQuery/images/02_09_06_09.jpg" title=" ">

		<info><![CDATA[<p>Would repeal the Second Amendment which does not specify a purpose for firearms, and state that people have the right to firearms for "hunting, sport, collecting, and personal defense."</p>]]></info>
		<copyright><![CDATA[&copy; 2011 AP Images]]></copyright>
	</photo>
	

</gallery>

