<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<gallery accordion="true">

	<directions>
		<![CDATA[<p>View this slideshow about the history and debate over the ERA.</p><p>Select "Continue" to begin.</p>]]>
	</directions>

	<photo src="flash/jQuery/images/02_09_05_01.jpg" title="Alice Paul">
 
		<info><![CDATA[<p>Alice Paul introduced the idea of an Equal Rights Amendment to Congress in 1923. It states that women and men shall have equal rights under the law. Early in U.S. history, women had few legal rights. For example, they could not own a business, vote, or have custody of their children. By 1923, when the ERA was introduced, some rights for women were protected by law. The 19th Amendment, granting women the right to vote, for example, was ratified in 1920.</p>]]></info>
		<copyright><![CDATA[Public Domain]]></copyright>
	</photo>
	
	<photo src="flash/jQuery/images/02_09_05_02.jpg" title="Women working in a factory">

		<info><![CDATA[<p>However, Alice Paul and many other Americans believed that an ERA was still required to protect women&acute;s rights. They talked about issues such as lower pay than men for the same types of work. Each year, from 1923 to 1972, the ERA was introduced in Congress but failed to pass. Both major political parties expressed support for the ERA during these years.</p>]]></info>
		<copyright><![CDATA[Medioimages/Photodisc]]></copyright>
	</photo>
	
	<photo src="flash/jQuery/images/02_09_05_03.jpg" title="ERA supporters gathering in 1977">

		<info><![CDATA[<p>Supporters of the ERA grew in number. In 1972, Congress passed the ERA, meaning it was now proposed to the states. Congress placed a deadline of seven years on the amendment. Now it was up to the states to ratify it. The Constitution does not state whether a deadline should exist for ratification of an amendment.</p>]]></info>
		<copyright><![CDATA[© 2011 Jupiterimages]]></copyright>
	</photo>
	
	<photo src="flash/jQuery/images/02_09_05_04.jpg" title="Number of States that Ratified the ERA in Each Year">

		<info><![CDATA[<p>Many states ratified within the first year. However, ratifying votes quickly slowed down. Americans against the ERA were gathering support and raising concern. Thirty-five states ratified the ERA in total, three states short of the 38 needed for ratification. Five states even rescinded (took back) their ratification of the ERA!</p>]]></info>
		<copyright><![CDATA[© 2011 Jupiterimages]]></copyright>
	</photo>
	
	<photo src="flash/jQuery/images/02_09_05_05.jpg" title="1978 NOW march in Washington, DC">

		<info><![CDATA[<p>With the deadline quickly approaching, ERA supporters appealed to Congress to extend the deadline. Congress approved and gave the states until mid-1982 to ratify the amendment.</p>]]></info>
		<copyright><![CDATA[&copy; 2010 AP Images]]></copyright>
	</photo>
	
	<photo src="flash/jQuery/images/02_09_05_06.jpg" title="Deadline Passed">

		<info><![CDATA[<h3>Info</h3><div><p><li>Idaho was one of the states that took back their ratification. The National Organization of Women (NOW) challenged the state of Idaho&acute;s rescission in court. Supporters of the ERA did not think it was constitutional to take back a ratifying vote. Eventually, the case came before the Supreme Court. The Supreme Court ruled that states had the right to rescind ratification. It also ruled that the court case was no longer relevant, because even with those fives state the amendment still was not ratified.</li></p></div><h3>More Info</h3><div><p><li>The Equal Rights Amendment failed to gather three more states by the 1982 deadline. Since then, it has repeatedly been reintroduced in Congress. Some Americans believe Congress should pass a law allowing the ERA to ratify with three more state votes, rather than starting the process again. Virginia even ratified the ERA in February 2011. As part of the 1982 ruling, however, the Supreme Court ruled that the deadline extension was unconstitutional. Even the process of ratifying this amendment is controversial!</li></p></div>]]></info>
		<copyright><![CDATA[&copy; 2010 AP Images]]></copyright>
	</photo>
	
	<photo src="flash/jQuery/images/02_09_05_07.jpg" title="ERA NOW! or ERA YES!">

		<info><![CDATA[<p>Why are people against the ERA?<br /><br />Many Americans, both men and women, are concerned about the possible effects of the ERA. People worry that the ERA would end laws that protect women in the workplace, such as losing a job because of pregnancy. They fear that laws like these, specific to men or women only, would be seen as against the Constitution because of the ERA. They also raise concerns about the possibility of women being drafted into the military and losing the right to benefits after the death of husbands. Most of all, they say that current laws make the ERA unnecessary. </p>]]></info>
		<copyright><![CDATA[© FLVS]]></copyright>
	</photo>
	
	<photo src="flash/jQuery/images/02_09_05_08.jpg" title="STOP ERA!">

		<info><![CDATA[<p>Why are people against the ERA?<br />Many Americans, both men and women, are concerned about the possible effects of the ERA. People worry that the ERA would end laws that protect women in the workplace, such as losing a job because of pregnancy. They fear that laws like these, specific to men or women only, would be seen as against the Constitution because of the ERA. They also raise concerns about the possibility of women being drafted into the military and losing the right to benefits after the death of husbands. Most of all, they say that current laws make the ERA unnecessary.</p>]]></info>
		<copyright><![CDATA[© 2011 Thinkstock]]></copyright>
	</photo>
	
	<photo src="flash/jQuery/images/02_09_05_09.jpg" title="Your thoughts">

		<info><![CDATA[<p>What do you think? Should the ERA be ratified? Should Congress be allowed to put a deadline on ratification for any amendment? Discuss these ideas with a trusted adult.</p>]]></info>
		<copyright><![CDATA[ ]]></copyright>
	</photo>
	

</gallery>